RESUME BENJAMIN PETER EGGE

CONTACT DETAILS

1 Egret Place

Claremont Meadows, New South Wales 2747

Email: penrith1318@gmail.com Mobile: 0434 853 174

OBJECTIVE

I am currently looking to move into a position where I will bring a wealth of skills, experience to an organisation with the same spirit that I possess and where my skills and knowledge are directly transferable.

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled business professional with a 4 year exceptional career as the Director of Training within a Registered Training Organisation directing its Eastern States branches and an outstanding 10 year career within Corrective Services New South Wales.

Have been a manager in what is considered the flagship correctional centre for the State of New South Wales. Renowned for being a self starter and possessing the ability to achieve results and meet core business objectives.

My highest achievement was managing the Acute Crisis Management Centre at Long Bay for 18 months with the lowest number of industrial disputes and workplace injuries. My management practices of the Acute Crisis Management Centre resulted in a number of international corrections organisations being interested in emulating my practices within their own organisations.

In my capacity as a Director with Valiant Training I achieved the highest student results within an adjustable budget and was the only Director to never fall below budget expectation and maintain the highest standards.

The highlight of my employment with Valiant Training was the introduction of an international training partnership with the Israel Defence Force for high risk non-weapon system training for law enforcement and security industry staff. The partnership was a first for Australia and was quite successful within its customer base.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Manage Teams
Public Speaking
People Performance

Staff Training
OH&S Consultation
Negotiation Skills

Innovation and Change Risk Management Customer Service

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2012 - Current, Self Employed Platypus Training PTY LTD

I am currently self employed jointly owning Platypus Training PTY LTD. My company provides consultancy and team building training to organisations within NSW.

2009 – 2012, Director of Eastern States, Valiant Training

I had risen quickly to the position within the Valiant Group. I have made a reputation for being a highly motivated senior manager who achieves all objectives with highly driven staff.

1999 - 2009, Correctional Officer, Long Bay Complex

In my ten year career as a Correctional Officer I worked up to the position of Senior Assistant Superintendent. I was officer in charge of the Acute Crisis Management Unit at Long Bay for 18 months.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Diploma of Public Relations, Publicity and Marketing

Cert IV Security and Risk Management

Cert IV Occupational Health and Safety

Cert IV Training and Assessing (TAE40110)

Cert III Correctional Practice

Cert III Security Operations

Cert II Security Operations

OH&S Construction Industry Induction Rail Safety Worker Certificate ACT Safety for Industry Course Senior First Aid I am currently enrolled in The Law of the European Union at Europa Institute, Leiden Law School, Switzerland via correspondence. I envision I will complete this course by the end of 2012

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

I have been recently honored by being made a notable resident of the Penrith City Council area for my contributions to society by my work and actions.

I am the honored recipient of an Australia Day Council Award, Penrith City Appreciation Award, 2013 presented by the Premier of NSW for my work within the local community after being nominated as a local Australian of the year for 2012.

I received a Bronze Bravery Medal by the Royal Humane Society of NSW and by the Governor of New South Wales for rescuing 5 prisoners from smoke filled cells at Long Bay Correctional Complex.

ASSOCIATIONS AND REPRESENTATIONS

2012 - present - The Australian Bravery Association

I am a full member of the Australian Bravery Association.

2010 and 2011 – The Safety Show and Materials Handling Expo

I have attended and represented Valiant Training and the Valiant Group at the Safety Show and Material Handling Expo for the last 2 years.

2011 City of Wanneroo Council (Western Australia)

I have been the guest speaker to the Youth Councilors of Wanneroo City Council in Western Australia regarding communications skills and connecting to younger people who do not respect those in positions of authority.

2010 and 2011 University of Western Sydney

I have been the guest key note speaker to the Residence Assistants at the University of Western Sydney.